MUHAMMED YASSER MUSLIM

Java Back End Developer

+201014129303



muhmdyasser0@gmail.com



sharqia, Egypt



SUMMARY

Thinking "out of the box" to provide software-based solutions Strong in design and integration problem solving skills. Expert in Java, and MySQL with database analysis and design. Skilled in developing business plans, requirements specifications, user documentation, and architectural systems research. Strong written and verbal communications. working with Databases: MySQL ,SQL Server. Software:Apache Tomcat, Xampp, (NetBeans, Eclipse, IntelliJ),Postman ,SQL Server Mangement Studio and workbench

EDUCATION

Studying

Computer Science At Faculty Of Computer and Information Zagazig University 09/2019 - 09/2024

SKILLS

- Java Core and Network
- Object Oriented Programming and Design
- Data Structure and Algorithm
- Problem Solving
- Base System Analysis and Design
- Database (MySQL, SQL Lite, SQL Server, MongDB)
- Java EE (Servlet, JSP, JSTL, JSF)
- Spring (Core, Data (Hibernate), MVC, RESTful API, Boot, Security)
- Junit Testing
- Jasper Report
- Swagger
- Docker
- · Spring Cloud
- Spring Microservices
- Web Service (RESTful API)
- Git ,GitHub

CERTIFICATIONS

- Udemy: Java SE, Oop, Java Database certification.
- ITCRC: Mysql Database
- Udemy: Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Data and Spring Boot

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Database Developer

In Ideal System Company | 08-2022- Present

- Creating database objects such as tables, indexes and clusters
- Inserting and deleting data from a table
- Updating existing data in a table
- Using functions such as SQL database triggers, stored procedures and database views
- · Tabling aliases and column aliases
- Generating and understanding an execution plan

C# Desktop Developer

In Ideal System Company | 06-2023- Present

- Design, develop, and maintain desktop applications using C# and the .NET framework.
- Write clean, efficient, and maintainable code following coding stand
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to gather and analyze software requirements.
- Conduct thorough testing and debugging of software applications to ensure high-quality deliverables.

PROJECTS